# **Scott Farmer**

### Marketing & Creative Director

# Summary

Scott is an agile marketing and creative professional with over 20 years of experience in fast-paced agency environments with many business growth successes to his credit.

Multi-faceted experiences as marketing director, creative director, and business owner have honed Scott's unique skills to keenly distill complex business concepts from key stakeholders into targeted and creative marketing communications. As a digital marketing specialist, Scott has successfully helped many small and medium-sized companies grow and compete nationally and larger businesses to compete in local markets. Client markets have included both B2B and B2C.

Scott is a conceptual thinker who is passionate about creating meaningful, creative and effective marketing that helps align and grow business for his clients.

# Experience

#### Creative Director at Kinetix Group, LLC - Marketing & Creative Services

June 2004 - Present (12 years 9 months)

Partner: Responsible for the agencies complete creative and marketing operations.

Marketing and creative services. Scott successfully drives brand objectives for local and national B2B and B2C companies regularly achieving high market impact through a creative-analytical approach.

#### Hands-on:

- Digital marketing specialist
- Both branding and re-branding services
- Conceive and execute campaigns that articulate brand strategies and tactics
- Drive awareness and loyalty across digital, social, and print media.
- Account management, cross-functional teams and vendor management with P&L and budget responsibilities
- Regularly integrate marketing concepts into actionable creative design execution
- Content marketing
- Staff management

Creative Director: Scott has over 25 years of experience in the creative and graphic arts. He is traditionally trained and a digitally savvy creative and able to keenly translate marketing objectives into design excellence across all digital and print platforms.

#### Hands-on:

- Develop and execute creative from inception to finished piece
- Digital Savvy: content development, digital marketing, social media campaigns, digital content design, and analysis (conceptualization through execution)
- UX/UI and front end Web development
- Email marketing and social media campaign development and execution
- Expert print and pre-press experience
- Variable data digital and print campaign design and execution
- Staff Management: Provide creative and art direction for client staff and vendors including cross-functional teams. Manage and direct third-party and cross-functional vendors including designers, photographers, videographers, writers, talent, printer vendors, digital designers, and developers (US/abroad)
- Collateral design, sales materials, social media, POP, packaging, display, exhibit, outdoor, newsletter, and Web design

#### Chief Creative Officer at Bullzi Strategies, LLC

2000 - 2004 (4 years)

Directed day-to-day operations of the marketing, creative graphic design, and video teams including hands-on development of creative concepts through final execution.

Responsible for the development and management of 10 member marketing, digital design, and separate video departments. Also collaborated with cross-functional development teams.

Defined strategies and objectives, executed campaigns, performed all graphic design functions.

#### Bullzi Strategies, LLC

A leader in "variable data" marketing solutions including variable print, websites, videos, DVD's, broadcast media, and digital media campaigns.

"Variable data" marketing - Every revolution of the press and all digital media changed depending upon a clients/users preferences. Resulting in a more robust user experience, deeper client relationship, and higher sales.

- Specialized in "variable data" marketing strategies and content development for both B2B and B2C clientele.
- Collaborate effectively with key stakeholders and interdisciplinary teams.

- Brand and identity development and integrity.
- Digital marketing, and print campaigns both corporate and retail.
- Managed all aspects of the digital design and videography teams (10 members).
- Cross-functional team management with programming department (35 developers).
- Corporate and consumer marketing strategies and execution.
- Creative and art direction for all staff and vendors including cross-functional teams.
- Creative conceptualization, graphic design and execution across both digital and print.
- Social media campaigns and content, analysis and continual improvement.
- Project manage and P&L responsibilities.
- Manage and direct third-party vendors including designers, photographers, writers, PR, voice over, and talent. Manage all print pre-press, press, and post finishing services.

#### **Executive Creative Director at Tri Star Visual Communications**

1996 - 2000 (4 years)

Directed day-to-day operations of the marketing and creative graphic design teams including hands-on development of creative concepts through final execution.

- Brand and identity development, awareness/engagement, and integrity management.
- Recruited, coached, and managed graphic design team.
- Project manage and P&L responsibilities.
- Collaborate with key stakeholders and business owners on all marketing and design projects.
- Creative conceptualization, graphic design and execution.
- Managed prepress and press runs over 1MM with budgets also over \$1mm.
- Lenticular lens (3D and Morph images) design and print across corporate sales, retail sales, ad display, product tip-in, and retail products.

#### Managing Partner at Design Consultants, Inc

1983 - 1996 (13 years)

Managed day-to-day operations, provided full-service marketing and graphic design services. Developed and managed client, financial, and vendor relationships.

# Skills & Expertise

Marketing Strategy
Creative Direction
Marketing
Social Media Marketing
Branding & Identity
Brand Management
Graphic Design
Computer Graphics

**Brand Development** 

**Strategic Planning** 

**Pre-press** 

**Digital Photography** 

Videography

**Project Management** 

**Business Process** 

**Value Propositions** 

**Creative Strategy** 

**UX Design** 

**Email Marketing** 

**Email Newsletter Design** 

**Graphical User Interface (GUI)** 

Photo manipulation

**UI Design** 

**Content Strategy** 

**Contract Negotiation** 

**Real Estate Transactions** 

**Real Estate License** 

**Real Estate Marketing** 

**Website Building** 

**Search Engine Optimization (SEO)** 

**Digital Video** 

**Art Direction** 

**Interactive Creative Direction** 

**Agile Methodologies** 

Web Design

**Scriptwriting** 

**Successful Business Owner** 

**Front-end Design** 

Illustration

**Pre-press Operations** 

**Press Checks** 

print specialist

**UX/UI Designer** 

# Volunteer Experience

#### Assistant Scoutmaster at Boy Scouts of America

September 2004 - Present

Volunteer for Troop 131 and Pack 131 for the last ten years

#### Volunteer at Pinnacle Peak Park, Scottsdale, AZ

November 2013 - Present

Volunteer

#### Chapter Advisor at Order of the Arrow BSA

2012 - Present

Order of the Arrow, Wiki Pa Chapter, Brotherhood member

# Education

#### Millersville University of Pennsylvania

Bachelor of Arts (B.A.), Dean's List Honors, Design and Visual Communications

Activities and Societies: Artwright Advertising - Graphic Designer; Studio Artist; Millersville Univ. Art Gallery Docent Millersville University of Pennsylvania Gallery Docent Millersville University of Pennsylvania Art Studio Recipient

# Certifications

# **REALTOR®** and GRI Designated

State of Arizona

# **Graduate of REALTOR Institute, GRI Designation**

National Association of REALTORS®

# **Scott Farmer**

Marketing & Creative Director



# 3 person has recommended Scott

"While at my previous employer, I hired Kinetix Group to help us with rapid development of a comprehensive branding plan in support of a total website upgrade and Hubspot marketing program. Scott was a master of extracting the core essentials of our brand and, more importantly, why our customers should care."

— **Paul Hughes, MBA**, C.O.O. and Board Director, Guardian 8 Corporation, managed Scott at Kinetix Group, LLC - Marketing & Creative Services

"When I need expert and balanced guidance for my clients marketing needs I call Scott. Insightful, creative, and professional are just a few qualities he possesses. His ability to design a comprehensive marketing approach from data and see it through all aspects of production is remarkable. I know my clients save both time and money from his expertise. Scott's ability to analyze a clients current plan, understand the disconnects while suggesting a way forward is rare and valuable to any firm. To get his type of insight firms typically have several staff members. I appreciate that Scott has been in the owners chair, managed staff, dealt with bankers and payroll, and designed many digital and print campaigns for a variety of markets and clientele. From my perspective, this has given Scott great insight into business and what works and does not work in marketing and how to grow businesses. I have come to rely upon his ability, for both myself and my clients, to clearly see the finished product from the very start. I recommend Scott with two words: Unique, Valuable."

# — **Christine Dura**, *CEO* and Founder, Dura Consulting, worked with Scott at Kinetix Group, LLC - Marketing & Creative Services

"Whenever I need something done well, and especially when it needs to be fast and right, I turn to Scott. He listens to our design needs, recommends options based on current best practices, and then delivers excellent work. Many times I couldn't have done it without him. A great eye, excellent design sense, and always very professional."

— Ran Farmer, Senior Managing Director, ARPC, was Scott's client

Contact Scott on LinkedIn